PROFESSOR: So, what does
this algorithm do?
Is a complete?
That is, if a solution exists, is
it guaranteed to return one?
Well, it's a little tricky.
But we're going to have to answer
this for each of the problems.
Is it optimal?
Is it guaranteed to find
the least cost path?
OK.
Think about it for breadth
for a search.
We're going to answer
it for all of them.
In general, we're going to also think
about the time complexity and the
space complexity.
Time complexity is, basically,
how many nodes get expanded.
Space complexity is, basically,
how big can the fringe get.
OK?
We're going to answer all these
questions with the following cartoon
of a search tree.
These are my cartoons.
So they're not brilliant like
Katrina's cartoons.
But here's what they're
going to look like.
OK?
All right, that's the mountain.
You can see the resemble, I hope.
All right, so this is
your search tree.
At the top of the search
tree is the start node.
What's right below it?
Some other nodes that you
can get to in one step.
They're going to be b of them.
b the branching factor
of the search problem.
It's, kind of, the average or the
maximum number of actions available
from a state.
So there's one node at the top.
The next layer has b nodes.
If I go two steps in the forward,
that's b squared nodes.
And so, if I go all the way down
to the bottom, well how
deep is this tree?
Well, it's however deep
it can possibly be.
So M is the maximum depth.
OK?
How many nodes are on
the bottom layer?
b to the m, right?
We could figure out whether or not
there's a plus one or something.
But it's b to the M.
And that means that if there are
solutions at various depths.
OK, so I'm going to-- in red-- draw
these solutions at various depths.
And how many nodes are
in the entire tree?
Well there's b to the m at the bottom.
But then there's all that
stuff above it.
Well how many are there?
Well, there's one plus b, plus b square,
plus blah, blah, blah, blah.
All the way to b of the m.
And really that's just, actually,
b to the m, right?
B is usually bigger than two.
OK, so basically this thing is
exponential, where the base is the
branching factor.
That's how quickly it grows.
And the exponent is how did
you might go on this tree.
That's going to help us think about how
much work we do in these various
algorithms.